

Miyamoto Lab, Tokyo Institute of Technology 4259 Nagatsuta, Yokohama, Kanagawa

Z zuo.c.aa@m.titech.ac.jp

🞧 realzuoc · 🛅 chen-zuo

Specializing in the development of Optical Wireless Power Transmission (OWPT) applications and Laser safety technology, I bring a robust background in the design and implementation of VCSEL-based systems and the advanced safety solutions towards the operation of Lasers. My academic foundation encompasses optical design, semiconductor physics, and photovoltaic, complemented by practical skills in computer vision, system control, and automation. I excel at integrating these disciplines to innovate and enhance system efficiencies in OWPT projects.

Professional Experience

Miyamoto Lab, Tokyo Institute of Technology PhD Course Student

Kanagawa, Japan Oct 2021 – Present

- Advisor: Associate Prof. Tomoyuki Miyamoto
- Theme: Advanced Optical Wireless Power Transmission Safety System towards Error-free Safety

FIRST, IIR, Tokyo Institute of Technology Research Assistant

Kanagawa, Japan Oct 2022 – Present

• Project: Development of the IoT application and the control system for indoor Optical Wireless Power Transmission System.

Research Outcomes

- Advanced OWPT Safety System towards Error-free Safety.
 Fundamental Investigation of Camera-based Safety System of OWPT.
- 3. OWPT using VCSEL and GaAs Solarcell. Jan 2021
- 4. A Novel GaN Power Converter.

 Aug 2020
- 5. Arduino-based smart home system development. Apr 2020
- 6. Photoelectric Detection Based Auto-Tracing PID Smart Car. Oct 2019

EDUCATION

Tokyo Institute of Technology

Tokyo, Japan

ongoing

July 2023

MEng. in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

Nov 2021 - July 2023

Dissertation: Fundamental Investigation of Camera-based Safety System of Optical Wireless

Power Transmission (Top 10% With Outstanding Award)

Advisor: Associate Prof. Tomoyuki Miyamoto

Changshu Institute of Technology

Suzhou, China

Bachelor of Engineering in Optoelectronic Information Science and Technology

Sep 2017 - Jun 2021

Thesis: Mode Characteristics Analysis of The Ridged Waveguide

Advisor: Prof. Ming Yang

Skills

Programming&Hardware Python, Matlab, STM32, C, Arduino, LATEX

Tools Matlab, COMSOL, Lighttools

Languages&Test English(IELTS 7.0), Chinese(Native), Japanese(Primary), GRE 317

RESEARCH Interests

- Short-Mid-Long Range Optical Wireless Power Transmission
- Laser Safety and Automatic Laser Emission Control
- Vertical Cavity Surface Emitting Laser
- Object recognition and intrusion detection

Selected Publications

- 1. Chen Zuo, and Tomoyuki Miyamoto. 2024. "Camera-Based Safety System for Optical Wireless Power Transmission Using Dynamic Safety-Distance" Photonics 11, no. 6: 500.
- 2. Chen Zuo, and Miyamoto Tomoyuki. 2023. "Improvement of Optical Wireless Power Transmission Safety System Using Depth Camera by New Safety Distance." In The 5th Optical Wireless and Fiber Power Transmission Conference, OWPT11:05.
- 3. Chen Zuo, and Miyamoto Tomoyuki. 2024. "Integrative Dynamic Safety System for OWPT: Real-Time Velocity and Distance-Based Safety Control." In The 6th Optical Wireless and Fiber

Power Transmission Conference, OWPT06:02. SPIE.

Awards	Outstanding Master Student Award	2023
	Student Paper Award, OWPT2023	2023
	Excellent Undergraduate Thesis	2021
	University Scholarship, Second	2021
	University Scholarship, Second	2020
	Unviersity Scholarship, First	2019
	Excellent AIESEC Global Volunteer	2018